Welcome to the $600,000 studio.
I'm not saying that you need one of these,
but I'm
going to show you through some of the
things that I've implemented over the last
months to make content look and sound
that little bit crispier.
And I hate that the microphone's on my
hat.
I usually loathe that, but
this microphone here isn't going to cut it
because we're going to move around.
This is what? The Sennheiser MKH 416?
416.
Yeah. We like this one at the moment.
Before this, we were using a Shure SM7B,
which we put through
a RodeCaster. Now, this device here
is called a Cloud Lifter.
It, in essence, makes that sound better.
If you get the new one of these,
the RodeCaster 2, that has that built in.
And if you get the new one of these,
the Shure SM7DB, it has one of those built
in.
And the reason we like this shotgun mic,
shotgun because it
records kind of down the barrel, is
that this can plug straight into the
camera
that we're using, which is a Sony FX3.
I'll actually show you some of the other
cameras that we use in a second.
Let's go for a walk.
So here we have the main light
that we use.
What are these things called?
Oh, honeycomb grid.
This is a honeycomb grid.
You can keep that in the edit as well.
That just kind of softens the direction of
the light, right?
Yeah,
it kind of makes it more directional.
If we take that off, that light
is always way too harsh.
So it spills as well, whereas when it-
So it spills apparently. This is the term.
Maybe you should be in this video.
Then this light over here
is what we call a hair light.
So this-
Or a rim light.
A what?
Hair light or a rim light.
Hair light or a rim light. Look at this.
And that creates
that nice little shiny part on the side of
my face that
accentuates my fantastic jawline.
This is pretty much where we record the
majority of our content.
We are actually going to build another
studio in here, but this makes do for the
time being.
Considering it's only ever boys in here,
it's pretty messy.
I'll leave
props that we talk about in videos, books,
a selection of
caps because I'm going bald. What's
that thing called? A what?
Cheap reflector. [chuckles]
Is it called a cheap reflector?
It's just the cheap version.
Oh, it's just the cheap version.
Just in case you get lonely during the
edit.
[chuckles]
This is a teleprompter we use for some of
the modules in the course.
You put an iPad down on that,
and it reflects there,
so then you can stick your
camera in behind. And
if you ever see anyone holding one of
these in content,
it's because they're using a teleprompter.
In my business mentorship,
I promote using a Panasonic GH52.
This camera is so durable,
and the variable lens on this,
I've probably
recorded near 1,000 videos on this.
I did my entire big main YouTube channel
on my own using this.
I love these.
Having a variable lens just helps me so
much from a
cinematic standpoint.
You go really tight
when maybe you're creating B-roll about
something.
Then having the option of a wide lens,
that's now redundant.
You've got two of them, don't you?
I do have two of them,
but one of them I dropped.
Don't drop them.
They're durable, but don't drop them.
We don't really use that at the moment.
At the moment, we're using an FX3. And
if you ever wanted to know
if you're paying
your videographer too much,
his rig would look like this.
So we've got a Sony FX3 here,
35 millimeter lens.
We have something on the end called an ND
filter.
We have a Pro-Mist filter, which
is 1/8 strength.
A Pro-Mist filter?
What that basically does
is it makes the...
You can't see it on this camera, but
if you film that one with the light, it'll
basically mean that there's a halation.
It kind of blurs the light
and it softens the skin tones,
just makes it give it
more of a cinematic feel.
Yeah,
it does feel very cinematic recording
that.
And there's an ND filter on as well?
Yeah, we've got two filters. The mist
is behind the ND,
and the ND's at the front.
Now, again, we're getting very complex,
and I know some people are going to be
like, "What the hell
are you talking about?" The ND filter
stops letting in as much
light.
It's like sunglasses for your camera.
Basically, that means
that you can open the lens a bit wider,
which lets in more
light,
but the ND filter then stops it from being
overexposed, which gives you a
nice blurred background.
So pretty much you put sunglasses on your
camera, you get
a nice blurred background.
The rig on here,
you've got a battery pack, a monitor so
you can see what you're doing. And again,
this is real advanced stuff that none of
you need to care about or worry about.
But maybe in three to five years,
you'll have a Declan,
and he'll have a camera rig
like this on top.
Then we've got the FX handle.
XLR handle.
You've got the XLR handle on top.
So we can plug that in.
Which means, in essence, when we
are using a mic, whether it be a Shure
SM7B, plug that straight into the camera.
Because the way we
were doing it before was
that we would record
the footage on here.
We'd press record on the RodeCaster,
and then you
synchronize the audio up in line with the
footage so that you get your audio.
Most podcasts will record separately.
There'd be an audio track,
there'd be a video track.
That's why some people clap at the
beginning of a production,
or in the old days
with the films, they were like [claps] .
That's so you can line up the audio with
the video to make sure that it's crisp and
lovely,
which you will need to do with that,
but then Premiere and DaVinci do it
for you. Should we swap back?
Yeah.
By the way, guys, quickly,
if you're a personal trainer,
there's a link in the
description for my PT starter pack,
which is a program designed just for
personal
trainers.
And if you're not a personal trainer,
there's going to be another link
below it where I want to give you 30
business bits of advice over the next 30
days,
completely free. It's in your inbox.
If you don't love them,
you can unsubscribe at any point.
Okay, back to the rest of the video.
Here's what I have,
and I call it the productivity corner.
Truth be told, when we launched Nutonic,
for some reason, our US
orange cans,
we just didn't get the flavor right.
I think they sent it to me.
They said,
"We can't sell this." Cracked can.
I was like, "Ah,
it'll be fine." Chris Williamson was like,
"We cannot sell this."
So we had to destroy loads of them.
I said, "Just send them somewhere.
Let's just give them away for free." They
were like, "Nope." So I think we maybe
lost nearly $100,000 worth of stock,
which was shite.
But I said, "Send me a pallet,"
which they did, and I drink them.
I think they're fine. For me,
I don't care about the taste as much as I
care about
the benefits. Those are not released yet,
so don't go too close to them.
They should be out later this week. Very,
very exciting times.
This is the love of my life at the moment.
I'll be honest with you,
the first week I bought this,
I thought I'd made a massive
mistake. These cars,
you can lift the front axle,
but it still scrapes on the odd
thing. The bum has a rear diffuser on it.
These little diffuser wings at the back,
they can scrape.
Although, every time something like
that happens, I just go on a forum online,
and GT3 owners are like, "Get used to it.
Scrape in the front?
Get used to it." This
is quite cool how the door handles come
out.
The Audi RS6 is an amazing car.
But the three things I didn't like about
the Audi:
it's too quiet. This is very loud.
I've always fancied an Alcantara steering
wheel,
which is like the suede steering wheel.
And I really love
that this one's a manual,
which sometimes in traffic you think,
"I wish I had the PDK."
But being connected to the gears
is something I miss.
Growing up in the UK,
we learned how to drive manual.
Did you learn to drive manual here, Miles?
Again, the bucket seats that are in here,
the first week, I was like, "Ah
Have I bought a car that's uncomfortable?
But it took me two,
three weeks before I finally was like,
"I love it." I think for
the first few weeks, you're petrified,
or you think about the amount of money
you've spent on it, and you think,
"What am I doing? What's the point?
I could have made financially smarter
decisions that could have helped my
son." But then you drop it into second
and go to 9,000 RPM, and you think,
"Fuck him." I don't want to spoil him,
because that's what happens, right?
If you do well in life
and you leave loads to your kids,
they turn out to be little
shit bags. So every bit of money
that I don't spend
financially smart,
looking after my son and my family
is good,
because if we hit financial troubles
and we lose everything, that'll be
great for his mindset. If anything,
the more reckless I can be with my
money,
the more I'm setting up my son for
success. You buying this?
[car revving]
You ready to get gassed up?
The exhaust fumes can't be too bad for
you, can they?
Matt Armstrong, at the moment,
is rebuilding one of these, the GT3 RS,
which
is just like this, but better,
and $350,000 more.
But let me tell you why I didn't get the
RS.
If I was to get the GT3 RS,
instead of having these two vents here,
where there's a radiator or two radiators,
or one radiator?
A radiator at the front,
even though the engine's at the back.
I get all this trunk space, which
is great for jujitsu.
I've got all my kit, got all my gear,
put it in here, bit of storage.
If I was to get the GT3 RS,
I wouldn't have anywhere to put my jujitsu
kit.
I also couldn't afford it.
But more importantly, it was the storage,
not the
extra $350,000. It was the storage.
Repeat after me, Declan.
It was the storage.
[engine starting]
[engine revving]
All right,
before we die of carbon monoxide
poisoning, that's enough.
[inhaling] [exhaling] Do you know what
that smells like? Happiness.
Happiness. [door closing] So
if you don't shut the door
properly,
the window doesn't shut.
Every time it torrential rains, part of my
brain,
you know the part in most people's brains
they go, "I left the door open,"
or, "The oven's on." I think to myself,
"I bet I left my window open." So
every time it rains,
I'm just there worried.
[door closing] That is just the sex.
I'm sorry, but
take the repayments.
Another thing that's worth noting
is finance,
100%. Other car, finance, 100%.
Every single person with
nice cars, even people that
are super wealthy, they finance it.
It just doesn't make sense to put all your
money in one place, because that same
several hundred thousand dollars,
we could buy more stock of Nutonic,
or we could invest in another business,
or we could buy shares in a startup.
No matter how wealthy you get,
just finance it and get a warranty.
That's what I'd say. Finance and warranty.
So even if, say,
you're in your first few years of running
a business, I'll tell
you this, getting an M3 or an RS6
or even getting a
six-year-old Golf R,
you will feel just as happy.
Because I feel like with this channel,
I want to be your older brother.
I was giving you this advice the other
day.
Go to a dealership, get pre-owned,
get a warranty.
Three years, fine. Anything goes wrong,
not my problem.
So this is a gym,
but no one trains here because technically
it's not a gym, this
is a studio. I'll explain why this
is kind of important.
My main business for years has been a
personal training business, and one of the
things that we don't really talk about
is... Well, we do talk about it.
The first three seconds of content
is so important.
So if I walk into set and go,
"When it comes to fat loss, there
are three things
that are more important than..." Actually,
do you know what?
We've been through this.
I hate starting videos with
that for a start.
When people go, "Here
are three things about fat loss,"
and then number one is hit
a decent step count.
Scrap what you're doing
and just do a video about step count.
Rather than trying to get three subjects
and doing a poor job of each of them, just
pick each subject
and make an individual video.
Let's start again.
Imagine if there was a type of exercise
that you could do every single day.
You never get too sore from it,
and implementing it not only makes you
feel better,
not only de-stresses you
and gives you great ideas, not only
is this a way to spend
more times with your friends and family,
but could also play a really positive role
in your fat loss journey. That thing
is walking.
According to research, whatever.
Being in this scene,
someone that's never seen me before,
especially in this
TikTokification of social media,
the fact that we are served content based
on our
interests, not based on who we follow,
straightaway you kind of know
what the video is about. Much of this
is just there to give people the visual
aid
to understand that I'm probably a fitness
pleb talking about fitness stuff.
If I'm here at home in the kitchen going,
"When it comes to fat loss, there are..."
Unless I'm going to actually talk about
food or something relative to the context,
it just doesn't make sense.
When it comes to getting stronger in the
gym, if this isn't an analogy or a
metaphor that I'm going to use to make a
point, then what's the point of including
it? It's why I think gym-based content
is really important, even for those of you
that don't have the luxury of a facility.
Even if you're in a PureGym, David Lloyd,
Virgin, whatever, use this as a
visual aid. Now, the problem
that a lot of you face
is you're in a squat rack,
there's a lot of background noise,
so you end up using a voice isolation
that makes
it sound like crap.
Some of you don't have a videography,
don't have a Declan.
I got a lot done in business before I had
a videographer.
You could just set up the camera.
So Declan, if you put
that camera down on that
bench.
So instead of being someone in the gym
that's kind of stood there with your
iPhone to the side
and you're a little bit nervous
and you're like, "When it comes
to performing the hip hinge movement,
it's really important." Instead of that,
you can just film yourself in the gym
doing the movement.
Then afterwards,
you can just take your microphone
and say the cue you were going
to say.
And now what Declan's going to do in the
edit is show you the footage that
was just there,
and I'm going to record the voiceover.
When it comes to performing the hip hinge
movement, first of all, take the knees
off lock. Now from here,
you're going to pretend there's an
invisible button on the
back of the room.
You're going to now break at the hips,
send your bum backwards to
touch that invisible button as your chest
comes closer to the floor.
Which means for a lot of you,
when it comes to doing exercise tutorials
or stuff in
the gym,
you can just point a camera to
that area Perform the
movement, then when you get home,
go into CapCut or whatever app it is,
and just do
a voiceover. And remember,
this isn't your workout of the day.
This is how you can help people.
If your lower back hurts doing an RDL,
then it's
maybe because of... If you're someone
that doesn't feel comfortable in the squat
rack, maybe try this.
When it comes to lining up the squat rack
to be the perfect
height for a squat,
it should go to this area of your body.
These whiteboards,
worth their weight in gold.
This is just a static piece of plastic
that sticks onto surfaces.
There's no glue. There's nothing.
For any of you out there,
you can write on it, put very poignant,
important words,
and this visual representation can
sometimes be so excellent for your
business.
So whether you're trying to make a point,
or maybe you're drawing
something that could help people
understand the context of the
point you're trying to make,
the whiteboard is excellent. These
are very cheap. You can get them online.
And I think that just having that static,
no gap between the wall and the back,
I've been using these since 2017. Amazing.
And again, with the natural light,
it's important to me that we have
that in a
place where I'm getting a nice amount of
lighting on me.
If I was to record the majority of my
content over there, it just wouldn't look
good as far as lighting.
That's why you'll never really see
anything filmed down
this end.
There's too much of a down light to it.
Just doesn't really work too well.
Got the punch bag.
This is just literally to have a bit of
fun with. The other day, the video.
We do one video and include that,
business write-off.
Use the dumbbells in video,
Why do you think the car
was in today's video?
[punch thudding] Ah! Was in Thailand,
didn't I?
Hey. Hey. Rowing machine,
obviously not mine. This is Bob.
Sometimes you just, you want to fucking...
You ever just go down the road and think,
"I would love to punch someone in the
face"? You ever think like,
wish I had a time machine so you could
literally just
crack someone in the chin,
then go back in time
and pretend you never did it.
Do you ever go like that? Yeah,
all the time. Sometimes, Bob.
[punch thudding] And we have the bathroom
around the side.
Now,
one of the reasons I'm making this video
is I think everyone should aspire to
have their own working space,
whatever it is that you do,
whether you're selling
real estate, social services,
personal training, whatever.
For me,
even though for years I filmed at home,
sometimes you need to get into the
mindset to go somewhere to do work.
There's no PlayStations here.
There's no TVs here. When I'm here,
I'm working.
Then when I go home,
although I have an office at home,
I don't like working in the
front room. It's my place to relax.
For years,
I would always go to a cafe to work.
I never do emails at home. For me,
there's such an important part of having
the
mindset that when you go to a certain
place, it's for a certain outcome.
Even when I worked in a budget gym,
I would go to Waitrose, sit in the cafe,
get all my work done.
I wouldn't leave the cafe till my work
was done.
In time,
I think you should all aspire to have a
business location for filming,
because having the backdrop
and the depth there,
I feel like it almost raises the
stakes a bit, where they go,
even though James is talking about pricing
or landing
pages or whatever,
he's not just filming it in a spare room
in his house.
He's gone to the effort to make a nice
facility.
We're going to build another studio up
there,
which suddenly going to get air con,
so I don't have to get sweat patches like
this, because it is fucking Australian
summer, mate.
We're going to put a podcast studio in
there, and we're going to run
the podcast at a loss just to get
attention, just to get ears on, traffic to
certain websites. Very excited for that.
What have I missed out, Declan?
What did you
think when you first came here?
I suppose the crazy thing, right,
is people come
past and they think it's a commercial gym,
and I have to explain to them, the worst
use of time for me at this stage of my
career would be to train people here.
Even if someone came in and went, "Hey,
mate,
I'll give you $500 for a PT session,"
just literally,
quite literally isn't worth it.
Not because I'm some amazing trainer
or whatever, just all of you within your
businesses, at the moment,
selling slots of time for hours is
absolutely what you should do. But then,
as you start to create systems within
building a social media platform,
sending people to certain resources.
Like this video,
I'm just going to say to people,
if you're a personal trainer,
there's a PT starter pack in the
description,
and if you're a general business
owner that isn't a PT,
there's another link where I want to give
you 30 days of
business advice. So yeah, this
is a behind the scenes to pretty much how
we
run and operate the Content HQ.
You ever walk past people's houses and
just go, "I'd love to be inside there"?
Not like as a creep.
Not like I want to go in
and kick the old woman down
and sleep in her bed and eat
the food in her fridge.
You just kind of want to know what it's
like inside.
That's what this is. When your neighbor
is selling their house and there's an open
house and you go in and walk around.
You ever do that? Yeah, no, me neither.
That's what this video is. Anyway,
hope you enjoy.
And as per usual,
YouTube's going to recommend this video
here, and it thinks that
if you're a smart bugger
and you enjoy content,
if you enjoyed this one at all,
you'll love this one. So give it a go. Oh,
wow.